<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on Jen-Chieh&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://www.jcs-profile.com/categories/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on Jen-Chieh&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.jcs-profile.com/categories/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>First static site generator</title>
      <link>https://www.jcs-profile.com/posts/web-dev/first-static-site-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jcs-profile.com/posts/web-dev/first-static-site-generator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m recently hooked by the static site generator, hence I have decided to create
one for myself. Why not? The huge reason is that I could host the site using
the GitHub&amp;rsquo;s static site hosting services, but the one I have previously created
in 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;https://jcs090218.github.io/blog/2018/11/12/Legacy%20-%20%E8%88%8A%E6%96%87/API-Reference-Template%20-%20API%E5%8F%83%E8%80%83%E6%A8%A1%E6%9D%BF/&#34;&gt;API-Reference-Template&lt;/a&gt;.
is server base, which is not generator base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The static site generator isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to create, the most valuable technology
is the frontend and UI/UX. However, I have already created the frontend for
my own use. The main task for me would just have to extract the server base
to generator base. I have also renamed the tool to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SiraDoc/SiraDoc&#34;&gt;SiraDoc&lt;/a&gt;,
so then I&amp;rsquo;m able to use it for other sites as well! Just like the previous
website, yet a lot easier and more suitable for the GitHub Actions&amp;rsquo; environment!
😉&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parallax Website</title>
      <link>https://www.jcs-profile.com/posts/web-dev/parallax-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.jcs-profile.com/posts/web-dev/parallax-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jcs-profile.com/public/AAU/wnm249/m15/wnm249_final/&#34;&gt;MapleStory Survival Kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the final project from the first class of web development from our
school. I joined this class as an elective class so I could have a peek of how
web development works. A list below is few highlights I would like to show from
this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parallax Effect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use of Sound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gashapon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-parallax-effect&#34;&gt;👁️ Parallax Effect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most parallax effect I have seen aren&amp;rsquo;t quite satisfied to me. Generally they
will have a image at the back of other components then have it semi-stationary
to sit still at the place. In this project I would like to have a peek of how
CSS can do on 2016. Fortunately, after being learning animation system from
CSS I am for sure that the parallax effect I was to imagine are possible to
accomplish by just the CSS without using JavaScript. You can use the small
panel on the top left corner to navigate through the four pages from this website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
